<?xml version="1.0"?>
<quiz><title>Evolution and the Origin of Biodiversity</title><timer>300</timer><question><text>Which of the following best describes biogeography as evidence for evolution?</text><option id="a">The study of how organisms are distributed globally and how island species reflect evolution and geological change.</option><option id="b">The analysis of fossils to understand the distribution of extinct species.</option><option id="c">The comparison of DNA sequences to show relationships among species.</option><option id="d">The observation of small-scale evolution in organisms with short life cycles.</option><correct>a</correct></question><question><text>Which of the following statements about homologous structures is correct?</text><option id="a">Homologous structures have the same function in different organisms.</option><option id="b">Homologous structures are similar in related organisms because they were inherited from a common ancestor.</option><option id="c">Homologous structures have reduced in size due to evolution and are no longer used.</option><option id="d">Homologous structures are unrelated to common ancestry and arise from direct observation.</option><correct>b</correct></question><question><text>Which of the following best describes the fossil record as evidence for evolution?</text><option id="a">It provides information about the global distribution of organisms.</option><option id="b">It documents the existence of now-extinct past species that are related to present species and allows dating for a timestamp that shows species distribution at certain periods in our planet's history.</option><option id="c">It shows the physical similarities between species that were present in a common ancestor.</option><option id="d">It involves the comparison of DNA sequences to show relationships among species.</option><correct>b</correct></question><question><text>Which of the following best describes analogous structures?</text><option id="a">Similar structures in related organisms inherited from a common ancestor.</option><option id="b">Similar structures in unrelated organisms that evolved to do the same job, not because they were inherited from a common ancestor.</option><option id="c">Structures that have reduced in size due to evolution and are no longer used.</option><option id="d">Structures that provide direct evidence for small-scale evolution in organisms.</option><correct>b</correct></question><question><text>What is the significance of molecular biology in providing evidence for evolution?</text><option id="a">It studies the global distribution of organisms and island species.</option><option id="b">It documents the existence of now-extinct species through the fossil record.</option><option id="c">It involves comparing DNA sequences to show relationships among species, such as transcription and translation.</option><option id="d">It observes small-scale evolution in organisms with short life cycles.</option><correct>c</correct></question></quiz>
