<?xml version="1.0"?>
<quiz><title>Genetics</title><timer>420</timer><question><text>Which of the following statements correctly describes non-Mendelian genetics?</text><option id="a">Non-Mendelian genetics follows all the laws of Mendelian genetics.</option><option id="b">Non-Mendelian genetics only applies to plants and not to animals.</option><option id="c">Non-Mendelian genetics involves inheritance patterns that do not follow one or more laws of Mendelian genetics.</option><option id="d">Non-Mendelian genetics cannot be used to understand any patterns of inheritance.</option><correct>c</correct></question><question><text>In the case of codominance, as illustrated by the red (R) and white (W) flowers, which of the following statements is true?</text><option id="a">Codominant alleles for red petals and white petals result in flowers that are entirely red or entirely white.</option><option id="b">Codominance occurs when both alleles are expressed equally in the phenotype of the heterozygote, resulting in flowers with both red and white petals.</option><option id="c">Codominance occurs when one allele completely masks the other.</option><option id="d">Codominance leads to a blend of the two traits, resulting in pink flowers.</option><correct>b</correct></question><question><text>The information gained from pedigree analysis allows for determining the nature of genes and alleles associated with inherited human traits. Based on the provided text, answer the following question: Which of the following statements is true regarding sex-linked traits?</text><option id="a">An X-linked trait can be passed from father to son.</option><option id="b">A Y-linked trait can affect females.</option><option id="c">An X-linked trait can NEVER be passed from father to son.</option><option id="d">A Y-linked trait affects both males and females equally.</option><correct>c</correct></question><question><text>Which of the following statements correctly describes the base pairings in DNA?</text><option id="a">Adenine (A) pairs with uracil (U), and guanine (G) pairs with cytosine (C).</option><option id="b">Adenine (A) pairs with thymine (T), and guanine (G) pairs with cytosine (C).</option><option id="c">Adenine (A) pairs with cytosine (C), and guanine (G) pairs with thymine (T).</option><option id="d">Adenine (A) pairs with thymine (T), and guanine (G) pairs with uracil (U).</option><correct>b</correct></question><question><text>Which of the following statements best describes the process of gene cloning?</text><option id="a">Isolating a gene of interest and inserting it directly into a human cell.</option><option id="b">Using a virus to transfer genetic material into an organism.</option><option id="c">Isolating a gene of interest, inserting it into a plasmid, cloning the gene in bacteria, and harvesting the gene from the culture.</option><option id="d">Directly observing the gene expression in multicellular organisms.</option><correct>c</correct></question></quiz>
